Welcome.
欢迎。
In the last lecture, we successfully add in this ledge check and now we have the ability
在上一讲中，我们成功地加入了这个壁架检查，现在我们有能力
to tell if the character has reached the ledge.
来判断角色是否已经到达窗台。
And the next step that we need to do, so if this condition is true, our character should
下一步我们需要做的是，如果这个条件是真的，我们的角色应该
climb up the ledge.
爬上窗台。
And for that, we'll need to download some new animations.
为此，我们需要下载一些新的动画。
So here I am inside of Mixamo with the correct character uploaded.
所以我现在在Mixamo里面，上传了正确的角色。
Instead of the search bar here, I'm going to search Climb and press Enter.
我不使用搜索栏，而是搜索 "攀登"，然后按回车键。
So there are many different animations here for that.
因此，这里有许多不同的动画，用于此。
And after some testing, I found out that, so I'm going to scroll down, this climbing
经过一些测试，我发现，所以我将向下滚动，这个爬升
to top works the best.
到顶部的效果最好。
So this is the one that I'm going to download.
所以这是我要下载的一个。
So I'm going to select this one.
所以我要选择这一个。
And there's one thing here that I'm sure you can notice.
这里有一件事，我相信你可以注意到。
So you can see the animation is moving the character mesh, but in here we don't have
所以你可以看到动画正在移动角色的网格，但在这里我们没有
in place option to tick.
And this is where things get tricky.
这就是事情变得棘手的地方。
So in order to climb up the ledge, this is something that we need to rely on root motion
所以为了爬上窗台，我们需要依靠根部运动来实现。
to achieve.
来实现。
So basically we'll need the animation to lift our character up.
所以基本上我们需要动画来提升我们的角色。
If we were to do this completely from code, it'll be extremely complicated to match the
如果我们完全用代码来做这件事，那么要将动作和动画相匹配就会非常复杂。
movement with the animation.
动作和动画相匹配。
So using root motion here would work the best.
所以在这里使用根部运动将是最有效的。
But for animations from Mixamo, after we convert the animations using Mixamo converter, the
但是对于来自Mixamo的动画，在我们使用Mixamo转换器转换动画后，根动作不会被转移到Mixamo中。
root motion won't be transferred to the converted version.
根动作不会被转移到转换后的版本。
In other words, we won't be able to use the root motion for this animation.
换句话说，我们将不能为这个动画使用根动作。
Let me quickly show you what that looks like.
让我快速向你展示这看起来像什么。
So I'm going to download this animation, click download and make sure you tick without skin.
所以我要下载这个动画，点击下载，并确保你勾选无皮肤。
So this is the first animation that we're going to get.
所以这是我们要得到的第一个动画。
And the second one, I'm going to search for hang in here.
第二个动画，我将在这里搜索挂。
And I'm going to scroll down.
然后我向下滚动。
So this is the second one that we're going to get.
所以这是我们要得到的第二个动画。
So this drop to free hang.
因此，这个下降到自由悬挂。
I'm going to click it and you can see for this animation, it doesn't have in place option
我将点击它，你可以看到对于这个动画，它没有到位选项
as well.
也是如此。
I'm going to download this one.
我将下载这个动画。
Every setting here checks out.
这里的每一个设置都是正确的。
Click download.
点击下载。
And next thing we'll need to go through the conversion process again.
接下来，我们需要再次进行转换过程。
So I'm going to go inside of this incoming FBX.
所以我将进入这个传入的FBX内部。
I'm going to delete all these animations inside.
我要删除里面所有的动画。
So press delete and click yes.
所以按删除键，然后点击是。
Next thing I'm going to paste the animation downloaded to here.
接下来我要把下载的动画粘贴到这里。
So select this clamping to top and select this drop to free hang.
所以选择这个夹子到顶部，选择这个下降到自由悬挂。
Control plus C and control plus V then.
然后控制加C和控制加V。
And I'm going to open this mix-melt converter.
我将打开这个混合-融化转换器。
Left click to continue, enter the conversion process, scroll down.
左击继续，进入转换过程，向下滚动。
And I'm going to click here to convert the animations.
我将点击这里来转换动画。
Alright the conversion is done.
好了，转换已经完成。
I'm going to close this window, go to this outgoing FBX.
我将关闭这个窗口，转到这个输出的FBX。
Then go back to my project.
然后回到我的项目中去。
I'm going to drag in those two animations.
我要拖入这两个动画。
So I'm going to go inside of this raw folder.
所以我要去这个原始文件夹里面。
Then I'm going to select this clamping to top.
然后我将选择这个夹子到顶部。
Then this drop to free hang.
然后把这个下降到自由悬挂。
And drag them to my content browser.
然后把它们拖到我的内容浏览器。
So every setting here should stay the same as the last time.
所以这里的每一个设置都应该和上次一样。
All we need to do now is to assign the skeleton in here.
我们现在需要做的是在这里指定骨架。
Then click import all.
然后点击导入所有。
And we have the animations here.
我们的动画就在这里了。
So I'm going to open this clamping to top.
所以我打算把这个夹子打开到顶部。
And you can see our mesh is moving.
你可以看到我们的网格正在移动。
So this indicates this is a root motion.
所以这表明这是一个根部运动。
But if I click the root bone here.
但如果我点击这里的根部骨骼。
So the red line here is our root bone.
那么这里的红线就是我们的根骨。
And this is not behaving the way that we want.
这并不是我们想要的行为方式。
So for this animation, we'll rely on this root bone to lift our character up.
所以在这个动画中，我们将依靠这个根骨来提升我们的角色。
And right now this root bone is not moving on the Z axis.
而现在这个根骨没有在Z轴上移动。
So this one here won't work.
所以这根骨头就不能工作了。
And same thing goes for this drop to free hang.
同样的事情也适用于这个下降到自由悬挂。
I'm going to double click to open it.
我将双击来打开它。
So this one is actually a bit more complicated.
所以这个其实是比较复杂的。
So we'll need to rely on the root bone to rotate our character.
所以我们需要依靠根骨来旋转我们的角色。
Then descend our character.
然后让我们的角色下降。
And right now it's simply moving on the X axis.
而现在它只是在X轴上移动。
So this one won't work either.
所以这个也不能工作。
Now you must be wondering, is there anything that we can do to fix this issue?
现在你一定想知道，我们有什么办法来解决这个问题吗？
Well, there are two in editor solutions.
好吧，在编辑器里有两个解决方案。
So the first one, in order to transfer the root motion successfully, we'll need to use
所以第一个，为了成功地转移根部运动，我们需要使用
a character from MixMath, then convert the mesh using the MixMath converter, then download
一个来自MixMath的角色，然后用MixMath转换器转换网格，然后下载
the animation.
动画。
The animation downloaded this way will have the root motion intact.
通过这种方式下载的动画将有完整的根部运动。
Then inside of Unreal Engine, we'll need to use IK rig to retarget the animation to our
然后在虚幻引擎中，我们需要使用IK rig来将动画重新定位到我们的
skeleton.
骨架。
This is quite a lengthy process and the root motion transferred this way can be quite problematic
这是一个相当长的过程，而且以这种方式传输的根动作可能会有很大的问题
sometimes.
有时。
And the second solution is, we can manually animate the root bone of our character using
第二个解决方案是，我们可以使用序列器中的
control rig inside of Sequencer, and the second one works much better than the first one.
在Sequencer中控制装备，第二个办法比第一个办法好得多。
By doing this, we'll also have manual control of how much we want the root bone to lift
通过这样做，我们还可以手动控制我们希望根部骨骼提升多少
the character up.
角色抬高的程度。
And this is the way that we're going to use.
而这就是我们要使用的方式。
We'll look at how we can do that in the next lecture.
我们将在下一节课上研究如何做到这一点。
So these are the two animations that I just downloaded and converted.
所以这是我刚刚下载并转换的两个动画。
Once you have the animations ready, we'll look at how we can actually add root motions
一旦你准备好了这些动画，我们将在下一节课看看我们如何能够真正地将根部动作
to them in the next lecture.
在下一节课上，我们将研究如何为它们添加根部动作。
I'll see you in the next lecture.
下一讲见。
[music]
[音乐]